Luis Gustavo Neves da Silva

luisgustavoneves@gmail.com • +55 21 97580-3198 • https://github.com/luisgustavoneves

Introduction

Senior developer with more than 10 years of experience implementing various projects in different environments and technologies areas, working in systems development and maintenance. Highlights are the capacity of self-learning, the production of results from research and the ability to work alone or in teams.

- · Python, Django
- FastAPI, Microsserviços
- JavaScript and TypeScript
- Vue.js

- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL
- Git, Gitlab
- Docker
- RASA, DeepPavlov, AIML

Experience

Petrobras – Petróleo Brasileiro SA, Rio de Janeiro RJ (2001 – until today)

Software Developer (2006 – until today): Design, development, production deployment and maintenance of various information systems. Leading projects individually, in teams and in collaboration with universities, using agile methodology.

- Olav Federation of Virtual Assistants. NLP, RASA, DeepPlavlov, AIML, ontologies, OWL/RDF, txt2peech, speech2txt.
- Manntis Computational Vision Framework applied to the Oil industry. Monitoring underwater footage, pattern recognition, deep learning, docker, GPU, videos overlay, FastAPI, microservices..
- GeoNet Web system for publishing data from well geophysics studies. Geo-navigation and map plotting of oil fields, well trajectories and other data using the technologies Leaflet.JS, GeoJSON.
- ICARO Intensive Computing Reservoir Optimization. Reservoir optimization system that generates several simulations from an original template, distributes and executes them in company computational clusters. HPC, Python, SSH, PBS, TORQUE.
- STRITA Django system for reservoir injectivity testing. Visualization of large amounts of data at different scales. Data optimization for the display of animated interactive graphic demonstrating the advancement of liquid injection in the different reservoir layers.
- SAGAS Django system with interface for Pre-salt layers gas solution calculation system, using JQuery and HighCharts Libraries.
- FoulingWeb Django system with interface for waste accumulation simulator in oil transport
 equipment subject to thermal changes (heat exchanges). This system is used in refineries and
 platforms of the company, assisting in the conduct of operation of these units. Handles large
 amounts of numeric data making use of the numpy library; SVG technology for navigable
 interactive maps creation.

 CMIP – Database of Microorganisms of Interest of the Oil Industry. Web system for control of the collection of microorganisms stored in CENPES laboratory. Django System with microscopy image library. MySQL and PostgreSQL

Infrastructure analyst at Petrobras (2001 - 2005): Installation and maintenance of Linux clusters, support for Unix and Linux Workstations users, X terminal clients configuration using Cygwin, LPI certifications, MS MOP, ITIL Foundation

SERPRO – Serviço de Processamento de Dados Federal (1996 – 2000) : Systems Development for the National Traffic Department, in Mainframe Natural / Adabas and Visual Basic. National registration of drivers, disambiguation of homonymous drivers, traffic tickets control and revocation of driver's license. Big masses of data

Associação Educativa Kappa – (1994 – 1995): Technical Teacher, English, Logic, Introduction to Programming

Education

Fundação Getúlio Vargas – Applied Mathematics Institute (EMap) - FGV,

Master's degree in Mathematical Modeling, dissertation "Information and Visualization in Scientific Systems" defended in 2014.

Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro – COPPE - UFRJ,

Postgraduate, MBP - MBA in Energy, Oil and Gas Management, 2006.

Universidade Federal Fluminense - UFF,

Postgraduate, Computer Science, 2000.

Training

Coursera - Brown University,

Coding the Matrix: Linear Algebra through Computer Science Applications.

Udacity,

Intro to Statistics, HTML5 Game Development, Web Development, Differential Equations in Action.

De Paul University.

Web Development With Python and Django Program.

RM Treinamentos,	
Presentation	Techniques

Brasas English Course.

Other Activities

Mentor in Hacking.RIO 2019

Speaker at Campus Party Brasília and Campus Party Natal, "Digital Transformation, New Interfaces".

Petrobras VoiceBots Challenge Organization, Campus Party Brasília and Campus Party Natal 2019

Big Kahuna (Organization) of Python Nacional Conference, PythonBrasil 2008

Published Article, "Stimulating the Use of 3D Animations in a Learning Environment. World Congress on Computer Science, Engineering and Technology Education" - WCCSETE 2006.